What's a well-meaning decision by one person is outright censorship to the next. What we now know is that this account, Texas Lone Star, was part of a wider Russian disinformation campaign, one that has since been taken down. Would that change your view? It would mine, because now it's a case of a coordinated campaign to sow discord. And for those of you who'd like to think that artificial intelligence will solve all of our problems, I think we can agree that we're a long way away from AI that's able to make sense of posts like this. So I'd like to explain three interlocking issues that make this so complex and then think about some ways we can consider these challenges. First, we just don't have a rational relationship to information, we have an emotional one. It's just not true that more facts will make everything OK, because the algorithms that determine what content we see, well, they're designed to reward our emotional responses. And when we're fearful, oversimplified narratives, conspiratorial explanations and language that demonizes others is far more effective. And besides, many of these companies, their business model is attached to attention, which means these algorithms will always be skewed towards emotion. Second, most of the speech I'm talking about here is legal. It would be a different matter if I was talking about child sexual abuse imagery or content that incites violence. It can be perfectly legal to post an outright lie. But people keep talking about taking down "problematic" or "harmful" content, but with no clear definition of what they mean by that, including Mark Zuckerberg, who recently called for global regulation to moderate speech. And my concern is that we're seeing governments right around the world rolling out hasty policy decisions that might actually trigger much more serious consequences when it comes to our speech. And even if we could decide which speech to take up or take down, we've never had so much speech. Every second, millions of pieces of content are uploaded by people right around the world in different languages, drawing on thousands of different cultural contexts. We've simply never had effective mechanisms to moderate speech at this scale, whether powered by humans or by technology. And third, these companies -- Google, Twitter, Facebook, WhatsApp -- they're part of a wider information ecosystem. We like to lay all the blame at their feet, but the truth is, the mass media and elected officials can also play an equal role in amplifying rumors and conspiracies when they want to. As can we, when we mindlessly forward divisive or misleading content without trying. We're adding to the pollution. I know we're all looking for an easy fix. But there just isn't one. Any solution will have to be rolled out at a massive scale, internet scale, and yes, the platforms, they're used to operating at that level. But can and should we allow them to fix these problems? They're certainly trying. But most of us would agree that, actually, we don't want global corporations to be the guardians of truth and fairness online. And I also think the platforms would agree with that. And at the moment, they're marking their own homework. They like to tell us that the interventions they're rolling out are working, but because they write their own transparency reports, there's no way for us to independently verify what's actually happening. (Applause) And let's also be clear that most of the changes we see only happen after journalists undertake an investigation and find evidence of bias or content that breaks their community guidelines. So yes, these companies have to play a really important role in this process, but they can't control it. So what about governments? Many people believe that global regulation is our last hope in terms of cleaning up our information ecosystem. But what I see are lawmakers who are struggling to keep up to date with the rapid changes in technology. And worse, they're working in the dark, because they don't have access to data to understand what's happening on these platforms. And anyway, which governments would we trust to do this? We need a global response, not a national one. So the missing link is us. It's those people who use these technologies every day. Can we design a new infrastructure to support quality information? Well, I believe we can, and I've got a few ideas about what we might be able to actually do. So firstly, if we're serious about bringing the public into this, can we take some inspiration from Wikipedia? They've shown us what's possible. Yes, it's not perfect, but they've demonstrated that with the right structures, with a global outlook and lots and lots of transparency, you can build something that will earn the trust of most people. Because we have to find a way to tap into the collective wisdom and experience of all users. This is particularly the case for women, people of color and underrepresented groups. Because guess what? They are experts when it comes to hate and disinformation, because they have been the targets of these campaigns for so long. And over the years, they've been raising flags, and they haven't been listened to. This has got to change. So could we build a Wikipedia for trust? Could we find a way that users can actually provide insights? They could offer insights around difficult content-moderation decisions. They could provide feedback when platforms decide they want to roll out new changes. Second, people's experiences with the information is personalized. My Facebook news feed is very different to yours. Your YouTube recommendations are very different to mine. That makes it impossible for us to actually examine what information people are seeing. So could we imagine developing some kind of centralized open repository for anonymized data, with privacy and ethical concerns built in? Because imagine what we would learn if we built out a global network of concerned citizens who wanted to donate their social data to science. Because we actually know very little about the long-term consequences of hate and disinformation on people's attitudes and behaviors. And what we do know, most of that has been carried out in the US, despite the fact that this is a global problem. We need to work on that, too. And third, can we find a way to connect the dots? No one sector, let alone nonprofit, start-up or government, is going to solve this. But there are very smart people right around the world working on these challenges, from newsrooms, civil society, academia, activist groups. And you can see some of them here. Some are building out indicators of content credibility. Others are fact-checking, so that false claims, videos and images can be down-ranked by the platforms. A nonprofit I helped to found, First Draft, is working with normally competitive newsrooms around the world to help them build out investigative, collaborative programs. And Danny Hillis, a software architect, is designing a new system called The Underlay, which will be a record of all public statements of fact connected to their sources, so that people and algorithms can better judge what is credible. And educators around the world are testing different techniques for finding ways to make people critical of the content they consume. All of these efforts are wonderful, but they're working in silos, and many of them are woefully underfunded. There are also hundreds of very smart people working inside these companies, but again, these efforts can feel disjointed, because they're actually developing different solutions to the same problems. How can we find a way to bring people together in one physical location for days or weeks at a time, so they can actually tackle these problems together but from their different perspectives? So can we do this? Can we build out a coordinated, ambitious response, one that matches the scale and the complexity of the problem? I really think we can. Together, let's rebuild our information commons. Thank you. (Applause)
Lo qué es una decisión bien intencionada para uno es una censura absoluta para la siguiente. Lo que ahora sabemos es que esta cuenta, Texas Lone Star, fue parte de una campaña de desinformación rusa más amplia, una que desde entonces ha sido eliminada. ¿Eso cambiaría su punto de vista? Cambiaría el mío, porque ahora se trata de una campaña coordinada para sembrar discordia. Y para quienes les gustaría pensar que la IA resolverá todos nuestros problemas, creo que estaremos de acuerdo que estamos muy lejos de que la IA pueda dar sentido a publicaciones como esta. Así que me gustaría explicar tres problemas entrelazados que hacen que esto sea tan complejo y que luego piensen en formas para abordar estos desafíos. Primero, simplemente no tenemos una relación racional con la información, Tenemos una emocional. Simplemente, no es cierto que más hechos harán que todo esté bien, porque los algoritmos que determinan qué contenido vemos están diseñados para recompensar nuestras respuestas emocionales. Y cuando tenemos miedo, narraciones demasiado simplificadas, explicaciones conspirativas y el lenguaje que demoniza a los demás es mucho más efectivo. Y además, muchas de estas empresas, su modelo de negocio está unido a la atención, lo que significa que estos algoritmos estarán sesgados hacia la emoción. Segundo, la mayor parte del discurso del que estoy hablando aquí es legal. Seria un asunto diferente si hablara de imágenes de abuso sexual infantil o contenido que incita a la violencia. Puede ser perfectamente legal publicar una mentira absoluta. Pero la gente sigue hablando de eliminar contenido "problemático" o "dañino", pero sin una definición clara de lo que quieren decir, incluyendo a Mark Zuckerberg, quien recientemente pidió una regulación global para moderar el habla. Y mi preocupación es que vemos gobiernos en todo el mundo implementar decisiones políticas apresuradas que podrían desencadenar consecuencias mucho más graves cuando se trata de nuestra charla. E incluso si pudiéramos decidir qué charla dejar o eliminar. Nunca hemos tenido tantas charlas. Cada segundo, se suben millones de piezas de contenido de personas de todo el mundo en diferentes idiomas aprovechando miles de diferentes contextos culturales. Simplemente nunca hemos tenido mecanismos efectivos para moderar la libre expresión a esta escala, ya sea impulsada por humanos o por tecnología. Y en tercer lugar, estas empresas (Google, Twitter, Facebook, WhatsApp) son parte de un ecosistema de información más amplio. Nos gusta echarles toda la culpa a ellos, pero la verdad es que los medios y los funcionarios electos también pueden desempeñar un papel igual en amplificar rumores y conspiraciones cuando quieren. Como podemos nosotros, al reenviar sin pensar contenido divisivorio o engañoso sin estar seguros. Estamos agregando más a esa contaminación. Sé que todos estamos buscando una solución fácil. Pero simplemente no la hay. Cualquier solución tendrá que implementarse a gran escala, escala de Internet, y sí, las plataformas, están acostumbradas a operar a ese nivel. pero ¿podemos y debemos permitirles que solucionen estos problemas? Ciertamente lo están intentando. Estamos de acuerdo en que no queremos que sean las corporaciones globales las guardianas de la verdad y equidad en línea. Y también creo que las plataformas estarían de acuerdo con eso. Y en este momento, están marcando su propia tarea. Les gusta decirnos que las intervenciones que están implementando funcionan, pero como hacen sus propios informes de transparencia, no se puede verificar independientemente lo que realmente está sucediendo. (Aplausos) Y seamos claros que la mayoría de los cambios que vemos solo suceden después de que los periodistas inicien una investigación y encuentren evidencia de sesgo o contenido que rompe las pautas de su comunidad. Sí, estas compañías tienen que jugar de verdad un papel importante en el proceso, pero no pueden controlarlo. ¿Y qué hay de los gobiernos? Muchos creen que la regulación global es nuestra última esperanza. en términos de limpieza de nuestro ecosistema de información. Pero lo que veo son legisladores que luchan por mantenerse al día con los rápidos cambios en la tecnología. Y peor, trabajan en la oscuridad, porque no tienen acceso a los datos para entender lo que está sucediendo en estas plataformas. Y de todos modos, ¿en qué gobiernos confiaríamos para hacer esto? Necesitamos una respuesta global, no nacional. Entonces el eslabón perdido somos nosotros. Son esas personas que usan estas tecnologías todos los días. ¿Podemos diseñar una nueva infraestructura para soportar información de calidad? Bueno, creo que podemos y tengo algunas ideas sobre lo que realmente podríamos hacer. En primer lugar, si nos tomamos en serio atraer al público a esto, ¿podemos inspirarnos en Wikipedia? Nos han mostrado lo que es posible. Si, no es perfecto pero han demostrado que con las estructuras correctas, con una perspectiva global y mucha, mucha transparencia, puedes construir algo que se ganará la confianza de las personas. Tenemos que encontrar una manera de aprovechar la sabiduría colectiva y la experiencia de todos los usuarios. En particular las mujeres, las personas de color y los grupos subrepresentados. ¿Porque adivinen qué? Son expertos en odio y desinformación, porque han sido los objetivos de estas campañas durante mucho tiempo. Y a lo largo de los años, han levantando banderas, y no han sido escuchados Esto tiene que cambiar. ¿Podríamos construir una Wikipedia para la confianza? ¿Podríamos encontrar una forma en que los usuarios realmente proporcionen ideas? Podrían ofrecer ideas sobre decisiones difíciles de moderación de contenido. Podrían comentar cuando las plataformas decidan implementar nuevos cambios. Segundo, las experiencias de las personas con la información son personalizadas. Mi fuente de noticias de Facebook es diferente de la de Uds. Igual sus recomendaciones de YouTube. Eso hace que sea imposible para nosotros examinar qué información está viendo la gente. Entonces ¿podríamos imaginar desarrollar algún tipo de repositorio abierto centralizado para datos anonimos, con privacidad y preocupaciones éticas incorporadas? Porque imaginen lo que aprenderíamos si construyeramos una red global de ciudadanos preocupados que quisieran donar sus datos sociales a la ciencia. Porque sabemos muy poco sobre las consecuencias a largo plazo del odio y la desinformación sobre las actitudes y comportamientos de las personas. Y lo que sabemos, la mayoría se ha llevado a cabo en EE. UU. a pesar del hecho de que es un problema global. Necesitamos trabajar en eso también. Y tercero, ¿podemos encontrar una manera de conectar los puntos? Ningún sector, y mucho menos sin fines de lucro, start-up o gobierno, va a resolver esto Pero hay personas muy inteligentes en todo el mundo. trabajando en estos desafíos, de redacciones, sociedad civil, academia, grupos activistas. Pueden ver algunos aquí. Unos construyen indicadores de credibilidad de contenido. Otros verifican hechos, para que las plataformas puedan clasificar noticias falsas, videos e imágenes Una organización sin fines de lucro, First Draft, trabaja con redacciones normalmente competitivas del mundo para ayudarlos a desarrollar programas de investigación y colaboración. Danny Hillis, un arquitecto de software, está diseñando un nuevo sistema llamado The Underlay, un registro de todas las declaraciones públicas de hechos conectado a sus fuentes, para que las personas y los algoritmos puedan juzgar mejor lo que es creíble. Y los educadores de todo el mundo están probando diferentes técnicas. para encontrar formas de hacer que la gente critique el contenido que consume. Todos estos esfuerzos son maravillosos, pero están trabajando en silos, y muchos de ellos no tienen fondos suficientes. También hay cientos de personas muy inteligentes. trabajando en esas empresas, pero de nuevo, esos esfuerzos pueden sentirse desarticulados, porque están desarrollando diferentes soluciones a los mismos problemas. ¿Cómo encontrar una manera de unir a las personas en una ubicación física por días o semanas, para que puedan abordar estos problemas juntos, pero desde sus diferentes perspectivas? ¿Podemos hacer eso? ¿Podemos construir una respuesta coordinada y ambiciosa, una que coincida con la escala y la complejidad del problema? Realmente creo que podemos. Juntos, reconstruyamos nuestros bienes comunes de información. Gracias. (Aplausos)